Twenty years. Two people.
One Day is a drama, romance film directed by Lone Scherfig.
A romantic comedy centered on Dexter and Emma, who first meet during their
graduation in 1988 and proceed to keep in touch regularly.
The film follows what they do on July 15 annually,
usually doing something together.
Emma Morley, played by Anne Hathaway.
Dexter Mayhew, played by Jim Sturgess.
Callum O'Neill, played by Tom Mison.
Tilly Shaw, played by Jodie Whittaker.
Ian Whitehead, played by Rafe Spall.
Alison Mayhew, played by Patricia Clarkson.
One Day is a 2011  romantic drama film directed by Lone Scherfig from a screenplay
by David Nicholls, based on Nicholls' 2009 novel of the same name.
It stars Anne Hathaway and Jim Sturgess, with Patricia Clarkson,
Ken Stott and Romola Garai in supporting roles.
It was released in the United States on 19 August 2011 by Focus Features and
in the United Kingdom on 24 August 2011 by Universal Pictures.
After meeting and spending the night together on St.
Swithun's Day on the eve of their college graduation, Dexter and Emma
are shown each year over 20 years on this same date.
A television series adaptation of the same source novel, starring
Ambika Mod and Leo Woodall was released on Netflix in 2024.
The film explores themes of based on novel or
book, comedian, love, author, writer.
The tone is emotional.